The first service
that is going to be very important for
us to deploy a global application is Amazon Route 53.
So, Route 53 is a managed DNS or Domain Name System.
And what does the DNS?
Well, DNS is just like a phone book.
It's a collection of rules and records,
which help clients find the right servers through URLs.
So let's go through the most common records in AWS.
For example,
say you are mapping www.google.com to an IPv4 address.
Then this is called an A record.
If you are mapping www.google.com to a long IPv6 address,
it's called the quadruple A record.
Also, if you map a host name to another host name,
so search the www.google.com come into the previous address.
It's called a CNAME because we're
mapping a host name to host name.
And then finally,
if you're mapping a host name into an AWS resource,
it's a special type of record called an Alias record.
And that works for you if you have an ELB,
or if using CloudFronts, S3,
an RDS database, et cetera, et cetera.
Now, going into the exam,
you don't need to know all the types of records,
but I just wanted to give you an overview of
them in this lecture.
So, from an Exam perspective,
Route 53 is a managed DNS,
but let's go one step further because you need to
understand a little bit better how it works.
So for example,
for Route 53 say,
we want to see what happens for an A Record.
So our Web browser is here.
That's a Web browser,
and we have an Application Server that we've deployed that
has a public IPv4.
Now we want to be able to access our application server
using a normal URL.
So for this, we're going to go into Route 53 and
we're going to create a, A Record.
And so that when the Web browser does
a DNS Request for myapp.mydomain.com
then the DNS will reply back with an IP.
And then that IP can be used by our Web browser to
get to our correct server.
and then get the HTTP Response from our server.
And this is the basics of how a DNS work at
a very, very high level.
What you need to understand as well for Route 53,
from an Exam perspective is the Routing Policies.
So, we need to know them at a high-level and decide what's
the right one based on the use case,
because you'll see, it's pretty simple.
So, the first one is called a Simple Routing Policy,
which has No health checks.
So our Web browser will go into our DNS system,
does a DNS query and gets an IPv4 for example as a result,
that's a Simple Routing Policy.
The basic one, we can understand.
The Weighted Routing Policy,
allows us to distribute the traffic across
multiple Institute instances.
So in this example,
we have to assign weights to our Institute instances,
for example, 70, 20, and 10,
and then our DNS we'll make sure that our clients have
70% of the traffic onto the first one,
20% of the traffic onto the second one and
10% of the traffic on to the third one.
This is effectively some kind of load balancing.
So in this Weighted Routing Policy,
we can use health checks.
Next, we have the Latency Routing Policy.
So in this example,
we'll say we are displaying our application globally,
one in California,
and the other one in Australia.
And our users are all around the world.
The Latency Routing Policy we'll look at where
the user is located.
And if they're located close to
our Kelly American Institute instance,
then they will be redirected to talk to that server.
And if they're close to Australia,
then they will be redirected to
talk to the Australia server.
And this is based on the latency.
So, in this example,
Route 53 will be used to minimize the latency between the
users and the servers by making the
users connect to the server.
That is the closest to them.
And then finally,
we have a Failover Routing Policy in which
we have a client and we have
a primary institute instance and a Failover one.
And so our DNS system will do a Health check On the primary.
And in case the primary instance fails,
then we will be redirected to the failovers.
This helps with disaster recovery.
So the clients will know exactly thanks to Route 53,
which instance to connect to based on the
health of that instance.
So that's it,
that's our the four Routing Policies you need to know.
Just a first one does not have a Health check.
All the other ones have Health checks and they
all serve different purposes.
So, Weighted Routing Policy is to distribute the
traffic across multiple institute instances.
Latency is to minimize latency and
Failover is to help with Disaster Recovery.
So hope that was helpful.
And I will see you in the next lecture.